《生活大爆炸》前情回顾
Previously on The Big Bang Theory...
可能我还不确定
I guess I'm still wondering
我跟艾米丽到底适不适合
if Emily and I are right for each other.
这不会跟喝咖啡的那个女生有关吧
Does this have to do with that girl you had coffee with?
你是说那位我魂萦梦牵的身心灵完美女神吗
You mean the strong, sexy angel I can't stop thinking about?
谁知道啊
Who can say?
我必须想出超级赚钱的点子
I need to come up with a big idea to make some money.
没理由不行啊
There's no reason you can't.
你说得倒容易
That's easy for you to say.
你和谢尔顿已经想出了超流氦模型
You and Sheldon already came up with your superfluid helium model.
那只是研究
That's just research.
根本没机会用来赚钱
We're never going to make any money from it.
去他的氦  这杯子里的旁趣酒
Forget helium-- the real superfluid
才是真正的超流逼
is the fruit punch in this mug.
让我想起我爸的秘密
It reminds me of my daddy's secret
"不许告诉妈妈"果汁
"Don't Tell Mama" Juice.
这个主意也许行
Maybe that's an idea.
给醉酒人士的导向系统
Guidance systems for drunk people.
早有了  叫优步叫车
They have that, it's called Uber.
在你的过冷氦试验中
Hey, in your supercooled helium experiments,
创建过量子漩涡吗
did you create quantum vortices?
有  怎么了
Yeah, why?
如果你建立一个导航系统
Well, if you made a guidance system,
是不是可以把漩涡当做螺旋仪使用
couldn't you use those vortices as a gyroscope?
我从来没想过
Wow. Never thought about that.
而且由于是在量子态下
And, since it's in a quantum state,
就能保持无限持续
it would maintain an infinite persistence.
开创性启示  热带鸡尾酒
Groundbreaking revelations, tropical drinks.
这简直是最棒的一集
Tell me this isn't like the
《欲望都市》了
best episode of Sex and the City.
我忍不住要问
Okay, I gotta ask--
你为什么要戴个领结
why are you wearing a bow tie?
我从来没申请过专利
I've never applied for a patent before.
我想给人家留下好印象
I wanted to make a good impression.
给人家留下你是搞笑人物的印象吗
Oh. Is the impression that your first name is Pee-Wee?
你自己还是个工程师呢
Yeah, well, you're an engineer.
这就是笑话  呛死你
End of joke, burn.
各位请进
Come on in, fellas.
你看  他也没系领带
See, he's not wearing a tie.
他是个专利律师
Well, he's a patent attorney.
可能他的领带也还在等待审核中
Maybe his tie is pending.
我看了你们的文件
So, I've reviewed your paperwork,
看起来我们申请专利需要的文件都齐全了
and it seems like we've got everything we need to file a patent
就是你们的无限持续陀螺仪
for your infinite persistence gyroscope.
-太好了  -太棒了
- That's great! - Excellent.
下一步是什么
So what happens next?
我们的法律团队会检查
Well, the legal team needs to review
来避免与已注册专利重复
existing patents to avoid overlap.
我觉得不会有
Oh, I don't think there will be.
因为我们自己研究搜过了
Yes, we did our own search.
挺好  但我觉得我们团队做得会更仔细
That's nice, but I think ours might be a bit more thorough.
这家伙好傻好天真
Get a load of this guy.
能想象我们用这玩意大赚一票吗
Can you imagine if we make money with this?
真的发财了  我就要挥霍
If we do, I am splurging
去买市面上最贵的鼻腔冲洗器
on the best sinus irrigator money can buy.
悲催的老故事
That old sad story--
某些人赚到点小钱  就都花鼻子里去了[吸粉]
guy gets a little money, goes straight up his nose.
只需要你们看看  然后签这份同意书
Just need you to review and sign this document
表示你们知道这项专利的所有权
acknowledging that you understand the university
有75%归学校所有
will own 75% of the patent.
75%吗
75%?
这也太扯了
That's outrageous.
这个点子是基于我们自己的研究
This is our idea based on our research.
你们哪来的理占绝大半的股份啊
How can you possibly justify owning a majority share?
大学政策就是这样
It's university policy.
我输了  我服
I know when I'm beat.
等等  等等  所以我们三个
Hold on, hold on. So the three of us
干了所有的活儿  却只能分到25%吗
do all the work and only end up with 25%?
霍夫斯塔德博士  本大学
Dr. Hofstadter, this university
付了你超过10年的薪水了
has been paying your salaries for over ten years.
你觉得我们这么做是因为善心大发吗
Did you think we do that out of the goodness of our hearts?
你说出这狠话之前  是有点这么以为
Well, until you just said that mean thing, kinda.
至于沃罗威茨先生
And as far as Mr. Wolowitz is concerned,
你作为一个从太空总署出借的联邦雇员
I'm afraid as a federal employee on loan from NASA,
你的名字是可以出现在专利上
your name can be on the patent,
但你无资格拿所有权股份
but you're not entitled to an ownership share.
所以  这个可能大赚特赚的东西
Wait, so this can turn out to be a financial success,
我屁都捞不着吗
and I get nothing?
有时候会给你颁发奖牌啊
Well, sometimes they give you a plaque.
这太不公平了
Well, that's not fair.
起码我们仨一人一个奖牌吧
We should all get plaques.
抱歉  我们不能签这同意书
Sorry, but we can't sign this.
走吧  我们走
Come on, let's go.
打扰了
Thank you for your time.
对奖牌我几个问题...
Couple of questions about the plaque...
你现在会有孕吐吗
So, have you been having any morning sickness?
稍微有点
A little.
而我的嗅觉提高也真够给我添乱
And it doesn't help that I've got this heightened sense of smell.
这是因为怀孕变这样的吗
Is that a pregnancy thing?
是啊
Yeah.
之前我就闻出了
The other day I sniffed out
华仔把慈善女童军饼干藏哪儿了
where Howie hid the Girl Scout cookies.
再也不吃巧克力夹心个屁
No more Tagalongs, my ass.
但至少你现在
But now you'll be able to make
可以自己做出配饼干喝的奶啦
your own milk to eat the cookies with.
各位好  佩妮
Hey, guys. Hey, Penny.
我真的很谢谢你愿意帮我这个忙
I really appreciate you helping me with this.
我真不知该怎么办了
I don't know what to do.
没事  让我看看
Oh, sure. Let me see it.
看什么
See what?
自从跟艾米丽分手后  我就没跟她联系过
I hadn't spoken to Emily since I broke up with her,
她在我家门口留下这个与字条
and she left this on my doorstep with a note.
"拉杰  我在分手前给你买的  不能退货了
"Raj, I got you this before we split up, but couldn't return it
我觉得你会想要它
And thought you'd like to have it.
迟来的情人节快乐  艾米丽"
Happy belated Valentine's Day, Emily."
真好
That's nice.
是好  还是想左右他的思想
Nice, or is she trying to manipulate him?
对啊  我是该拆开呢  还是还她呢
I know. I mean, do I open it? Do I return it?
你干嘛不拆开
Why wouldn't you open it?
她当时挺生气的
Well, she was pretty mad.
很有可能是一个代表我的巫毒娃娃
For all I know it's a voodoo doll of me
然后小鸡鸡被叉子插住
with a fork stuck in my junk.
你不会真觉得她会送给你
You don't think she'd actually send you something
恶心或危险的东西吧
gross or dangerous, do you?
有个办法可以知道  闻吧
I know one way to find out-- sniff this.
她只是怀孕  不是侦探猎犬
She's pregnant, she's not a bloodhound.
我闻到了一点机油味
Although I am getting a little machine oil.
我猜是金属类
I think it's metal.
来吧  拆开它
Come on, just open it.
在《权力的游戏》里
You know, on Game of Thrones,
巴隆·葛雷乔伊就收到装盒子里的他儿子的鸡鸡
Balon Greyjoy received his son's genitals in a box.
多一根  有备无患
Well, never hurts to have a spare.
这是什么
What is that?
这是个古董六分仪
It's an antique sextant.
水手使用这个配合星星来确认自身方位
Sailors used these to find their position by the stars.
真是个送天体物理学家的好礼物
What a nice gift for an astrophysicist.
对啊  她真有心思
I know, she's so thoughtful.
你看  她是想拐你回去
See, she's trying to get you back.
要是我  我也会买这个送你
Now, that is exactly what I would've gotten you
前提是我知道这是什么  还有你职业
if I had any idea what it is or what you do.
小爷我的自尊不容许这姑娘
You know, I have too much self-esteem to let this girl
用让我心怀愧疚的方式跟她复合
guilt me into getting back together with her.
不用怀孕  我的嗅觉都闻得出这屁话的味儿
You don't need to be pregnant to smell that load of crap.
如果我们绕开大学
Well, what if we go around the university
自己申请专利呢
and just get the patent ourselves?
不行  大学网站上有明文规定
We can't. It says on their Web site,
只要我们在这里工作  我们想出的所有点子
as long as we work there, they have a controlling ownership
他们都有控股权
of anything we come up with.
这下好了  我T恤的点子也归他们了
Great, so they own my idea for a T-shirt
那件印着"蠢如一麻袋地质学家"的T恤
that says "Dumb as a Bag of Geologists."
我们要么跟学校合作申请专利
Well, our choices are we do this with the university
要么就彻底放弃
or we don't do it at all.
反正不管怎样  我啥都捞不着
Either way, I get nothing.
又或者如果我们最后靠这个赚钱了
Or, if we ended up making money from this,
我和谢尔顿可以把我们的份额分给你
Sheldon and I could split our shares with you.
先说清楚
To be clear,
莱纳德说的是陀螺仪
Leonard is referring to the gyroscope,
不是T恤和马克杯
not the T-shirt and mugs.
靠  马克杯也归他们了
Oh! Now they own the mugs.
这也不失为一种解决办法
I guess that is a way around this.
你们俩愿意这么做吗
You guys would be cool doing it like that?
当然  任何利益我们都可以分成三份
Of course, we can split any profits three ways.
我无所谓
I'm fine with that.
好的  太棒了
Okay, great.
听起来...此处该有合同要签
It sounds like a, uh, contract might be in order.
当然  我们可以写份合同
Sure, we could write something up.
但写合同这种活该谁来干呢
But which one of us should be the party who...
你来吧  谢尔顿
You can do it, Sheldon.
就这么愉快地决定了
So stipulated!
有一我在他床底发现他藏的一叠合同[黄书]
Once I found a stash of contracts under his bed.
真是太诡异了
It was weird.
真好奇这玩意花了她多少钱
I wonder how much she spent on this.
那我们来查查
Ooh, let's find out.
钱不重要
It doesn't matter.
重要的是心意
It's the thought that counts.
是是是  重要的是内在美
Yeah, yeah, and beauty's on the inside,
胖瘦不重要  她花了多少钱
size doesn't matter-- how much she spend?
真的啦  我不想知道
Seriously, guys, I don't want to know.
老天
Oh, my.
拜托  你不能感叹完不告诉我啊
Oh, come on, you can't say "Oh, my," and then not tell me!
这玩意至少值500块
These things go for $500 and up.
靠
Damn.
我收到的情人节礼物只是一张明信片
All I got for Valentine's Day was a postcard
上面写着我的泰迪熊会延迟发货
saying my Vermont Teddy Bear was back-ordered.
好吧  所以她留下一份500块的礼物
Okay, so, she drops off a $500 gift
会有可能不是想要跟你复合吗
and she's not trying to get back together with you?
或许你说得对
Maybe you're right.
又或者艾米丽说的是事实  只是出于好心
Or she's telling the truth and just being nice.
或许你说得对
Maybe you're right.
哇  我真的很容易被人左右
Wow, I am easy to manipulate.
姑娘们  是艾米丽
Oh, guys, it's Emily.
我该怎么办
What should I do?
接吧  立场要坚定
Okay, answer it. Just be strong.
如果她开始哭  千万别答应任何事
And if she starts to cry, don't make any promises.
最重要的是  开免提让我们都能听见
And most importantly, put it on speaker so we can hear.
喂
Hello?
我是艾米丽
Hey, it's Emily.
现在方便说话吗
Is this a good time?
方便  有什么事吗
Yeah, yeah. Sure. What's up?
我留那个礼物你不介意吧
Was it okay I left that gift?
我真的很希望我们能做朋友
I'm really hoping we can be friends.
或许吧
Maybe, maybe.
你想一起喝杯咖啡吗
Um, you think you'd want to grab a cup of coffee?
还在听吗
Hello?
不好意思  我貌似得用超烦人超久的时间
I'm sorry, I seem to be taking an annoying amount of time
来决定我对此事作何感想
deciding how I feel about this!
我只是...怀念跟你在一起的时光
I just... I miss hanging out with you.
感觉我失去的不是一位朋友
It's not like I lost a friend,
我失去的是我的挚友
it's like I lost my best friend.
有没有可能你来我家一趟
Is there any chance you'd want to come over?
抱歉  我觉得这不是一个好主意
I'm sorry, I don't think that's a good idea.
好吧  我只是...
Okay. I'm just...
我现在真的很难过
I'm having a really hard time,
但那不关你事  是我自己的问题
but that's not your problem, that's mine.
我不会再来烦你了
I-I won't bother you again,
但请记住  我心里永远有一个位置属于你
but please know that you'll always have a place in my heart.
再见  拉杰
Bye, Raj.
你是一个好男人
You're a good guy.
再见  艾米丽
Good-bye, Emily.
真是太艰难了  姑娘们
That was rough, you guys.
我知道  但你做到了  我为你感到骄傲
I know, but you did it. I'm so proud of you.
那我先走了  不打扰你们闺蜜之夜
Well, anyway, I'll leave you to your girls' night.
你确定不留下来跟我们待在一起吗
Are you sure you don't want to stay here with us?
不了  我现在想自己安静会儿
No, I kind of feel like being alone right now.
如果你改变主意  我们会陪着你
Well, if you change your mind, we'll be here.
谢谢
Thank you.
帮我们向艾米丽问好
Say hi to Emily for us.
没问题
Will do.
这份合同我看行
This contract looks good to me.
当然看起来行啦
I'll say it looks good.
用的可是我的专属字体  谢尔维提卡体
It's in my proprietary font, Shelvetica.
我想说一些讨厌的话
I want to say something obnoxious,
但读起来的确挺舒服
but it is easy on the eyes.
我有点累了  华仔  可以走了吗
I'm a little tired, Howie. You ready to go?
等一下  我得先把合同签了
Yeah, one sec. I just need to sign this contract.
什么合同
What is it?
我的专利股份遇到了问题
Well, we ran into a problem about my share of the patent,
所以我们要建立合伙关系
so we're forming a partnership
平分我们获得的任何利益
to split anything we make equally.
谢尔顿  合同是你起草的吗
Sheldon, did you draft the contract?
当然是我啊
You bet I did.
你今晚一定能狠狠"爱"一发
You're gonna make out so hard tonight.
所以  你们打算不请律师过目一下
So, you're just gonna sign this
就直接签署文件了吗
without having a lawyer look at it?
不好意思
Excuse me.
在下从幼儿园起就开始起草合同了
I've been drafting contracts since kindergarten.
当年我拿手指乱涂乱画时不需要律师
Didn't need a lawyer to get me out of finger painting.
现在也就更不需要了
Don't need one now.
我知道  可是...
I know, but...
妮妮  他们俩是好心想办法
Bernie, the guys were nice enough to find a way
让我也能分一杯羹
to keep me from being cut out.
我也这么希望
Well, I should hope so.
毕竟这一切都是你的点子
The whole thing was your idea.
公平来说  霍华德的点子是基于谢尔顿的计算
Well, to be fair, Howard's idea was based on Sheldon's math.
各位  每个人对此都有贡献  好吗
Guys, everyone is involved in this, okay?
霍华德的发明
Howard's invention,
谢尔顿的计算  我原创的
Sheldon's math, my original theory
将时空视为某种过冷液体的理论
that space-time was like a supercooled liquid.
我相信佩妮如果此刻不是忙着啃倒刺
Which I'm sure Penny would've mentioned
她一定会指出这一点的
if she wasn't working on that hangnail right now.
啥
What?
亲爱的  没关系
Honey, this is fine.
如果你真的想签署由谢尔顿发起的合同
If you want to sign a contract that Sheldon whipped up,
那你就签吧
go ahead.
我能和你在外面谈一下吗
Can I talk to you in the hall?
-好的  -不好意思
- Sure. - Excuse us.
我说  莱纳德
Hey, Leonard.
怎么了
What?
如果她不认为我们应该申请这个专利
If she doesn't think that we should apply for this patent,
那她脑子绝对被"专"拍过
she's being patently absurd.
冷笑话不错
Good one.
太好了  你听懂了
Okay, you got it.
我还怕这个笑话太烧脑了呢
See, I was afraid it was a thinker.
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
我只是想确定你考虑清楚了
I just want to make sure you've thought this through.
还有什么需要考虑的  我们有了一个发明
What's to think about? We have an invention
现在想要推动它
and want to move forward.
华仔  你这是要和谢尔顿·库珀
Howie, you're about to form a legal partnership
建立法律上的合伙关系呀
with Sheldon Cooper.
如果你是想要冷静地提出无懈可击的观点
All right, if you're gonna calmly make excellent points,
那我就不想和你继续谈了
then I don't know if I want to talk to you.
好啦  我明白你的意思
Okay. I get it.
虽然你如此担心我  十分贴心
And it's sweet that you're worried about me,
但我可以照顾我自己
but I can take care of myself.
我不是担心你  我是担心我自己
I'm not worried about you. I'm worried about me.
我不想在整个孕期
I don't want to go through this pregnancy listening
都沉浸在你更加倍喋喋不休地抱怨
to you complain about Sheldon driving you crazy
谢耳朵是如何逼疯你的
more than you already do.
看吧看吧  你又搬出滴水不漏的逻辑来了
Here we go with the ironclad logic again.
你之前曾试着和他一起工作过
You've tried to work with him before.
结果可是一塌糊涂
It hasn't gone well.
凭什么这一次就会不一样呢
Why is this time gonna be any different?
难道是我儿的智商在帮助你吗
Is the fetus helping you?
如果是的话  这可算是作弊啊
'Cause that's cheating.
你好
Hello?
你好啊  拉杰
Hey, Raj.
我是克莱尔  你最近如何
It's Claire. How are you?
我很好  真的很好
Hi. I'm good. Really good.
我不知道自己为什么要说真的很好
Well, I don't know why I said "Really good."
我也就是一般的好吧
I'm just regular good.
我真的只是想听起来更有自信一些
I really just wanted to sound confident.
这个"真的"是真的"真的"
And that "really" was a real "really,"
不像第一个"真的"只是假装"真的"
not a fake "really" like the first "really."
真的吗
Really?
我不知道  我已经晕了  还错过了公路口
I don't know. I lost track and I missed my exit.
所以...你还好吗
So, uh... so what's up?
上一次我们打电话时
Well, last time we talked,
我刚刚和我男友复合了
I had just gotten back together with my boyfriend,
我想让你知道  我俩又吹了
and I wanted to let you know that things didn't work out.
真的吗  我很抱歉
Really? I'm sorry.
我发誓  我的词汇量远远不止这个
I swear I know other words.
所以如果你还有兴趣的话...
So if you were still interested...
有  绝对有  肯定有  毫无疑有
Yes! Indeed! Absolutely! Indubitably!
我不确定最后一个词的意思
I'm not even sure what the last one means,
但这至少是其他我会的词汇
but it's another word, and I know it.
那你什么时候想见见面呢
So, uh, when do you want to meet up?
我马上就要下班了
Uh, I'm almost off work.
你现在在干什么
What are you doing now?
现在吗
R-Right now, well...
其实  老实说
Well, actually, to-to be completely honest,
我准备去看望我的前女友
I'm stopping by to see my ex-girlfriend
因为她现在很难过  可是
because she's having a tough time. But...
这并不代表我俩会复合什么的
it's not like we're getting back together or anything.
让我猜猜  分手最难熬的地方
Let me guess, the worst part about breaking up
是她失去了挚友  从此无人可倾诉
is that she doesn't have her best friend to talk to anymore?
她的原话就是这个
That's exactly what she said!
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
我也是女人
I'm a girl.
这条算是撩汉手册的第一页内容了吧
It's, like, page one out of the playbook.
你能把这撩汉手册的电子版发给我吗
Any chance you could send me a PDF of that playbook?
他们出去好一阵了
They've been out there a while.
希望一切都正常
I hope everything's okay.
我在想他们到底在谈什么
I wonder what they're talking about.
如果你们闭嘴的话  我还可以告诉你们
If you guys would shut up, I could tell you.
装成啥都没发生的样子
Be cool, be cool, be cool.
你们没事吧
Hey. You guys all right?
没事  不过  我们谈了一下
Yeah. But, um, we were talking,
我开始有点担心
and... I'm a little concerned
咱们仨建立合作关系的事了
about the three of us forming a partnership.
你是建议我们成立有限责任公司吗
Are you suggesting a limited liability corporation?
因为我可没"有""任"识到这一点呢
'Cause I did not L-L-see that coming.
谢尔顿  我担心的不是钱或者其他事
Sheldon, my concern is not with the money or anything.
而是...你对我的态度
It's-it's with how you treat me.
我对你挺大方的
Well, I believe I'm treating you generously.
所以我才在合同里规定
That's why I've stipulated in the contract
你对我们的发明所作的贡献
that your contributions to our invention
与我同样重要
are as valuable as my own.
你是在说他的贡献不如你的重要吗
Are you saying that his contributions aren't as valuable as yours?
没有  我没有说
No, I am not saying that,
因为我说了一早上
because I kept saying that this morning
然后莱纳德告诉我"别再说了"
and Leonard said, "Stop saying that."
你看  我们每次合作都会变成这样
See? This is what happens every time we work together.
等一下
You know what, hang on.
如果让谢尔顿别无选择
What if Sheldon had no choice
只能放尊重呢
but to be respectful?
他脖子后面有什么开关
Is there a switch on the back of his neck
是我们还没发现的吗
we don't know about?
不是
No.
我是说  可以在合同中加一项条款
What I'm saying is you could add a clause to the contract
规定他不允许取笑霍华德
that he can't make fun of Howard.
怎么可能实行
How would you enforce it?
拜托  所有我签署的合同
Oh, please. Any contract I sign
都由我的道德准则强制执行
is enforced by my own personal code of ethics.
以及他的强迫症
And his obsessive-compulsive disorder.
对  这个也是
Yeah, that, too.
挪过去点
And scoot over.
你的部分影子坐进我的位置了
Part of your shadow's on my spot.
霍华德  你觉得如何
Howard, what do you think?
我同意
I'm on board.
我立马加上
I'll add it right now.
宝贝  补遗时间到
Oh, baby, it's addendum time!
你好
Hello?
艾米丽  听着
Hey, Emily, listen,
我不是很确定
I've been thinking, and I'm not sure
我去你家  会不会不太好
it's a good idea that I come over.
好的  我理解
Okay. I understand.
别  拜托别哭
No, no. Please don't cry.
好的  我不哭
Okay, I'll stop!
你好
Hello?
听着  克莱尔  计划有变
Hey, so, listen, Claire, change of plans...
行  你想怎样都好  但是她是在拐你
Fine. Do what you want, but she's playing you.
我觉得不是  她语气挺难过的
I don't think so. She sounded pretty upset.
你是说就像...
You mean like...
"我真的只想见见你而已
"I was just really looking forward to seeing you.
今天真是太难过了"
I'm having such a rough day."
艾米丽  听着
Emily, listen...
抱歉
I'm sorry,
但我不能过去
but I can't come by.
为什么不能
Why not?
我们心里清楚  如果我过去了
I think we both know if I come over,
我们就会复合  然后...
we're gonna get back together and...
我说了  我只是需要个朋友
I told you I needed a friend.
不然你觉得是怎么回事
What do you think is happening here?
稍候打给你
Call you right back.
我修正的部分从第四页开始
The-the revisions I made start on page four.
好多个"于是乎"
Wow. That is a lot of "whereupons."
你还没看到他给我写的情人节卡
You should see the Valentine's Day card he gave me.
"条款三  适用于本项目中
"Article three: As it pertains to this project,
谢尔顿·库珀博士承诺放弃
Dr. Sheldon Cooper promises to abstain from all insulting or
所有对霍华德·沃罗威茨使用
Disrespectful language
侮辱性以及轻视性语言权利
directed toward Howard Wolowitz,
包括但不限于以下  嘲笑工程学
Including but not limited to: mockery of engineering,
他的身高  发型  衣着
His height, his hair, his wardrobe,
以及他对电影《恶灵骑士》荒唐的信念
And his insane belief that the Ghost Rider movie
他居然说这电影"没那么糟"
was, quote, 'not that bad.'"
等下  也许可以加一条
Hang on. Maybe there should be
对我的"无侮辱"条款进去
a "No insult" clause about me, too.
你还喜欢香菜吗
Do you still like cilantro?
喜欢
Yeah.
你这是要逼死我啊
You're tying my hands here.
好了  我们赶紧签吧
All right, let's sign this.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
第六页的修改是什么
What are these changes on page six?
谢尔顿  你干了什么
Sheldon, what did you do?
我就知道
I should've known.
"谢尔顿·库珀收益中的25%
"25% of profits
将分配入霍华德·沃罗威茨与
"Due to Sheldon Cooper will be allocated to a scholarship fund
伯纳黛特·沃罗威茨夫妇长子/女的奖学基金"
for the firstborn child of Howard and Bernadette Wolowitz."
谢尔顿  你太好了
Sheldon, that's so nice.
完胜我在盖普童装给他们买的婴儿连体衣
That beats the onesie I was gonna get them from baby Gap.
太慷慨了  谢尔顿
That's very generous, Sheldon.
我一直认为教育重于金钱
Oh, I've always valued education over money.
而且你需要我作出书面保证尊重你这件事
And the very fact that you needed a written guarantee of respect
让我意识到一直以来
made me realize how dismissive
我对你的贡献有多不重视
I've been of your contributions.
我领情了
I appreciate that.
而且我只是希望
And I just hope
这份奖学金可以拯救你的孩子
that this scholarship can rescue your child
免遭工程师的次等教育
from the subpar education
与卑贱生活的悲惨命运
and menial life of an engineer.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
干嘛啦
What?
人家不是还没签呢嘛
I didn't sign it yet.
我理解你的意思
I hear what you're saying,
但我认识艾米丽很久了
but I've known Emily a long time,
我愿意相信她
and I think she deserves the benefit of the doubt.
好吧  这是你的生活
All right, it's your life.
不过你清楚结局会是如何
But you know how this is gonna end.
事实上我知道
As a matter of fact, I do.
我要去安慰她
I'm gonna comfort her,
因为我是一位有同情心又正派的朋友
because I'm a caring and decent friend
在她需要人话疗时
who's happy to be there
乐于陪在她身边
when she needs someone to talk to.
"聊"效不错
Good talk.